Contact

brunocaldeira@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ brunomarquescaldeira (LinkedIn) bruno-caldeira.github.io/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

User Experience (UX) Rapid Prototyping Wireframing

Languages

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual) English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

English - B1 GESE Grade 5 SELT

Bruno Caldeira

UX Designer / Product Designer London

Summary

I'm a UX/UI designer with a background in retail and telecommunication services at multinational companies. I love to create simple and creative solutions for big and complex problems.

I'm currently a user experience designer at Vodafone, leading the CRO program. Prior to Vodafone, I was an UI/UX designer at Currys PLC, where I was responsible for the user interface designs, analysis, wireframes and all UI/UX that was related to the CRO program.

Specialties: User Interface & User Experience, UX Analysis, Mobile & Web Product Design, Consumer Website Design, Prototyping, Figma

Experience

Vodafone UX/UI Designer March 2022 - Present (4 months) London, England, United Kingdom

- Engaged during the entire product lifecycle, using divergent and convergent thinking methods, exploring and prioritising a range of problems and solutions within a cross-functional team.
- Planning and analysing user research activities
- Producing concept sketches, wireframes, prototypes, interaction specs and other artefacts to support an effective user centred product development process
- Working with Product and front-end engineering, ensuring the best possible outcome from a visual and interaction design perspective

- Creating intuitive user interfaces and experiences for customers
- Producing pixel perfect design layouts that are technically possible within time frames and true to the user needs
- Applying brand and style guidelines to digital products and services
- Applying usability, interaction design and research theories and principles.
- Interpreting and applying data, research, competitor analysis, heuristic analysis and insights to inform design decisions and recommendations.
- Practical knowledge of UX role in agile Scrum methodology ways of working
- Presenting objective rationale to stakeholders for design decisions

Currys plc
UI/UX Designer
July 2018 - March 2022 (3 years 9 months)
London, United Kingdom

- Creating wireframes and prototypes for user testing purposes.
- Analysing user testing and running A/B tests to validate solutions
- Creating analysis for Conversion rate optimisation (CRO) purposes, includingcompetitor analysis, user insights, analytics data, heuristic analysis andrecommendations.
- Interpreting and applying data, research, and insight to inform design decisions
- User research analysis to understand customer behaviours and journeys
- Working alongside front-end developers and Marketing teams to bring ideas and concepts to life.
- Actively working with other designers, ensuring consistency across curry's website applying brand and UI guidelines.
- Presenting and defending designs to all levels of the business.

• Creating and presenting CRO and UX workshops

DrinkSupermarket.com Limited

4 years

Web Designer October 2014 - July 2018 (3 years 10 months) London

- Leading the product development, participating actively in brainstorms, creating sketches, wireframes, prototyping and developing pixel perfect visual layouts based on users behaviour and business requests using Adobe XD/ Photoshop as design and prototyping tools.
- Responsible for developing responsive pages based on high fidelity visuals, using HTML5, CSS3(with SASS) and jQuery, with Magento(PHP) e-commerce platform.
- Strong experience collaborating with back-end developers and Marketing team to bring ideas and concepts to life.
- Responsible for all digital visuals of DrinkSupermarket brand, such as website and affiliate banners, display animated/dynamic ads and social media artworks.
- Design and development of weekly email marketing campaigns, using photoshop, HTML/CSS and Mailchimp.

Web Design Intern August 2014 - October 2014 (3 months) London

- During my 3 months internship I've managed to redesign the whole DrinkSupermarket.com website, focusing on the user journey and experience. The process includes creating mockups, wireframes, prototypes and final visuals using Photoshop as a design tool and then coding those visuals with HTML/CSS(SASS) on Magento platform.
- Responsible for all website graphic designs such as Homepage banners, brochures and product images.

Self Employed - Freelancer

Front End Developer

June 2013 - October 2014 (1 year 5 months)

São Paulo Area, Brazil

User interface design based on its target audience and product/service,
 Programming websites from scratch, Wordpress Front end Development,
 Adapting existing websites to meet business requirements, Testing websites to identify any problems, Accessibility and W3C standards driven, Cross-Browser development.

Mint Digitall
Planner Assistant
April 2013 - June 2013 (3 months)

- Data survey and identify sources of information;
- Analyze data, generating diverse viewpoints and insights for the development through market planning, branding, communication, trends and behavior;
- Monitor customers social media and digital platform as well as their competidors;
- Presentation and briefing elaboration;
- Monitoring, logging and analyzing research results;
- Understand client needs to help Web Designers to transform ideas in layouts.

London, England
Cultural Exchange
August 2012 - March 2013 (8 months)
London, United Kingdom

Marco Marketing Consultants

2 years 6 months

Marketing Analyst

June 2010 - February 2012 (1 year 9 months)

São Paulo

Coordination of the audition process of Intel Inside Program.

Analysis of all co-branded activities executed by companies as Login (Brazil), XtraTech (Peru), Lanix (Mexico) and OEM's like HP, DELL, Sony, Samsung, IBM, Lenovo and Itautec.

Decision maker of penalties and reimbursement approvals.

Co-branded activities analysis (reimbursements);

- Campaigns feedbacks (penalties/denials);
- Saving-orientation (over U\$ 500K per year);
- POEs and POPs inventory control;
- · Process enhancements to speed up audit;
- Weekly report to internal stakeholders;
- · Research plans development;
- · Analysis research results;
- Marketing strategies.

Admin Assistant

September 2009 - June 2010 (10 months)

São Paulo

- Daily and weekly reports (Excel PROCV, Dynamic Spreadsheet);
- Financial routine requesting advances and proof of expenses to external employees;
- · Control and requests of Point of sale materials;
- Communication between external employees and human resources staff and IT;

Education

General Assembly

User Experience Design · (September 2021 - November 2021)

Universidade Paulista

Bachelor's degree, Marketing and Advertising (2008 - 2012)

Estácio

Marketing - 3rd Semester · (2007 - 2008)

Wizard by Pearson

Advanced English, English (2004 - 2009)